

☐ +1 551-263-9462 • ☑ yzhang31@wpi.edu

Summary

Ph.D. candidate in Data Science, with strong deep learning background and programming skills and the ability to work independently or as part of a research team. Broad research interests include:

deep learning

o meta-learning

o reinforcement learning

imitation Learning

o spatial-temporal data mining

o big data analysis

Education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute (WPI) Ph.D. Candidate in Data Science. GPA 4.0/4.0 Worcester, MA Expected 2022

Stevens Institute of Technology

Hoboken, NJ 2016-2018

M.S in Financial Engineering (Data Science Track). GPA 3.98/4.0

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Shanghai, China

B.E in Computer Science

2012-2016

Work Experience

Nuro, Behavior ML Team

Mountain View, CA

Machine Learning Engineer Intern

May 2021-Aug 2021

o Designed and developed new models for trajectory prediction and behavior planning for autonomous vehicles.

Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Worcester, MA

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2020-Present

o Assisted in teaching graduate courses including Reinforcement Learning and Database Management Systems.

Research Experience

Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Data Science Research Group

Worcester, MA Aug 2018-Present

Research Assistant

Funded by National Science Foundation

- o Proposed to combine generative adversarial networks with transfer learning framework in multiple source cities setup to solve the traffic estimation problem in a city suffering data scarcity.
- \circ Proposed C^3 -GAN which provides good embeddings for complex conditions through unique architecture and algorithm and thus solves the complex-condition-controlled generation problem.
- o Proposed a Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning algorithm which employed variational inference and deep neural networks to better capture the temporal uncertainties of time series data.
- o Proposed Curb-GAN which equipped with dynamic convolutional layer and self-attention mechanism to solve the spatial-temporal estimation problem.
- o Designed a novel generative adversarial networks to better capture the spatial patterns of spatial-temporal data.

Technical Skills

- **Programming:** Python, R, C/C++, Java
- Frameworks: PyTorch, TensorFlow, scikit-learn, NumPy, SciPy
- o Others: LATEX, Matlab, SQL

Publications

o [TIST] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Jun Luo and Zhi-Li Zhang. Urban Traffic Dynamics Prediction – A Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning Approach. In ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology.

- o [TIST] Gan Bao, Xun Zhou, Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, and Yiqun Xie. COVID-GAN+: Estimating Human Mobility Responses to COVID-19 through Spatio-Temporal Generative Adversarial Networks with Enhanced Features. In ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology.
- o [KDD] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Curb-GAN: Conditional Urban Traffic Estimation through Spatio-Temporal Generative Adversarial Networks. In Proceedings of the 26th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD '20).
- [ICDM] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou and Jun Luo. cST-ML: Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning for Traffic Dynamics Prediction. 2020 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).
- o [ICDM] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. TrafficGAN: Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation with Traffic Generative Adversarial Networks. 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).
- o [TBD] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation - A Traffic Generative Adversarial Networks Approach. In IEEE Transactions on Big Data.
- o [SIGSPATIAL GIS'20] Han Bao, Xun Zhou, Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Yiqun Xie. COVID-GAN: Estimating Human Mobility Responses to COVID-19 Pandemic through Spatio-Temporal Conditional Generative Adversarial Networks. In Proceedings of the 28th ACM SIGSPATIAL International Conference on Advances in Geographic Information Systems.

Conference & Presentation Experience

2020 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM) Conference Presentor	Virtual Event <i>Nov</i> 2020
26th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD '20) Conference Presentor	Virtual Event Aug 2020
2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM) Conference Presentor	Beijing, China Nov 2019
Graduate Research Innovation Exchange (GRIE) Poster Presentor	Worcester, MA Feb 2019
Awards	2020

Awards	
ICDM 2020 Student Travel Award	2020
Graduate Fellowship by National Science Foundation	2018-Present
Scholarship for international students from Stevens Institute of Technology	2016-2018